

# Tilsa Taboada M.

Paseo La Castellana 345 – Dpto. 302 – Santiago de Surco – Lima Perú 51 (1) 983483636 tilsa.taboada@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/tilsa-taboada

#### **SUMMARY**

Executive with experience of 8 years in the Commercial area in B2B companies of Technology and Informatics. Results-oriented, looking for new challenges.

Has great ability to lead and work as a team assuming challenges with responsibility and commitment, ensuring superior results than expected on the goals

#### **ENTEL PERU SA**

Entel Peru is a subsidiary belonging to the Entel Chile group. Today it has positioned itself as the leading operator of portability and customized technology solutions.

#### CORPORATE KEY ACCOUNT MANAGER - PERÚ (May 2018 - Apr 2021)

Lima, Perú

#### **EXPERIENCE**

- Responsible for the commercial management of the assigned portfolio, through the sale of Business Solutions and cloud solutions, seeking to increase Revenues, improve the profitability of the assigned portfolio and increase corporate customer satisfaction.
- Developed the value proposition for commercial executives, creating models of proposals, comparatives and training programs. I managed to increase Collaboration Solutions sales by 30% during the first 6 months
- It was possible to train the entire sales force (60 people), centralizing commercial information to streamline the sales process
- Participated in the monthly review of commercial results with the commercial director, identifying areas for improvement and proposing action plans.
- Responsible for the entire sales process: prospecting, pre-sale, sale and post-sale.
- Considered Top Entel



#### Products:

- Azure
- Google Cloud Platform
- Google Work Space
- Microsoft 365
- Infobip
- My Apps
- SOTI Mobil Control
- ESET
- Custom development

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **XERTICA Google Cloud Partner**

Google Premier Partner. Leading company in Latin America in Cloud, Collaboration and CRM solutions.

#### MM Sales Manager Perú - Ecuador (Jan 2017 – May 2018)

Lima, Perú

- Developed the value proposition to sales leaders and managers in 2 countries, creating compensation plans, incentives, and recognition & training programs.
- Drive the integrated sales plan and strategy to generate leads and create awareness of digital transformation.
- Planned create and commercialize technology solutions to attract, engage and transform companies through innovation.
- Work with the Marketing Operations and Demand Generation teams to create new outbound leads.
- Work with the Google team to generate new opportunities for the company and meet the objectives
- Prepared monthly performance reporting, gathering and synthesizing relevant data, leading analyses, identifying insights and opportunities, and developing final recommendations to present to senior management.

#### **CLOUDWARE 360 Google Cloud Partner**

Google Premier Partner.

### MM Sales Manager SMB Perú (Feb 2016 – Dic 2016)

Lima, Perú

- Management of SMB segment equipment.
- Accompaniment and follow-up to meetings with the team in charge.
- Indicator management
- Maintain growth in sales annually, complying with established budgets
- Consolidation of a commercial team
- Product training and sales process to new entrants
- Creation of Work Plan and coverage by quarter
- Compliance with personal and team quota

- Coordination and direct contact with clients of different segmentations.
- Responsible for searching, evaluating and qualifying new clients to determine potential and possible inclusion in the organization's portfolio.
- •Information gathering and needs analysis according to the client's profile, establishing and carrying out the activities and action plans associated with the business core.
- •Development of customer segmentation, according to the database provided. Quota compliance up to 170%

## **CONVERGIA PERÚ S.A**

## Administration and HR Analyst (Jan 2008 – Dic 2012)

Lima, Perú

- •People management.
- Preparation of payroll.
- •Administrative work with great results in worker satisfaction

#### **MASTER CENTER**

## Call Center Supervisor Convergia Regional (Nov 2006 - Dic 2017)

Lima, Perú

- •Training and updating of information for call center agents.
- Quality monitoring, response time, and abandonment rates.
- Attention to critical clients in 12 countries

## **EDUCATION**

**ESAN University** - International Specialization Program in Sales Management.

Nov 2017 - Dic 2018

## **Google University - Certification Courses**

- Google Educator
- Google Sales Representative
- Google Cloud Sales Representative

Cámara de Comercio de Lima - Diploma in Human Resources

Jan - Jul 2012

St. Ignatius of Loyola Institute – Communication Sciences

2004 - 2009

**Lenguages:** Spanish (Native), English Intermediate)

Interests: Peruvian folklore dancer, travel and peruvian cuisine